Finding Aid for G. Mennen Williams Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Governor's Papers
  - Chronological, 1949-1960
    - 1957
      - Military
        - Civil Defense
          - Meetings, Advisory Council, 2 folders (Box 385)
        - National Guard
          - General (Box 385)
          - Air Unit (Box 385)
          - Navy (Box 385)
        - Veterans
          - General (Box 385)
          - Apprentice Training (Box 385)
          - Bonus (Box 385)
          - Hospitalization (Box 385)
          - Organizations (Box 385)
          - Veterans Trust Fund
            - Lawrence Lalone, Executive Secretary (Box 385)
            - Administrative Reports (Box 385)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 385)
          - Veterans Vocational School (Box 385)
        - Selective Service (Box 386)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous
          - General [A-Z] (Box 400)
          - Foreign Aid (Box 400)
          - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 400)
          - Middle East (Box 400)
          - Surplus Property (Box 400)
        - U.S. Congress (Box 400)
        - U.S. Senate (Box 400)
        - General [A-Z] (Box 400)
        - McNamara, Patrick (Box 400)
        - Proxmire, William (Box 400)
        - Agriculture, Department of (Box 400)
        - General (Box 400)
        - Grain Standards (Box 400)
        - Air Force (Box 400)
        - Army (Box 400)
        - Attorney General (Box 400)
        - Defense, Department of (Box 400)
        - Federal Power Commission
          - General (Box 401)
          - Harris Gas Bill (Box 401)
        - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of (Box 401)
        - Housing (Box 401)
        - Interior, Department of (Box 401)
        - International Joint Commission (Box 401)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 401)
        - Labor, Department of (Box 401)
        - Navy, Department of (Box 401)
        - Postmaster General (Box 401)
        - State, Department of
          - General (Box 401)
          - Re: Africa (Box 401)
        - Legislation
          - Miscellaneous [A-Z] (Box 401)
          - Aid to Education (Box 401)
          - Area Redevelopment (Box 401)
          - Civil Rights (Box 401)
          - Fruit and Vegetable Markets (Box 401)
          - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 401)
          - Livestock Markets (Box 401)
          - Social Security
    - 1958
      - General Subjects
        - Administrative Reorganization of Government
          - General (Box 235)
          - Study Commission on Tax Administration (Box 235)
        - Adoption (Box 235)
        - Adult Education (Box 235)
        - Advertising (Box 235)
        - Aging Commission
          - Miscellaneous (Box 235)
          - General [A-L] (Box 235)
          - General [M-Z] (Box 236)
        - Aging
          - Employment of (Box 236)
          - Housing of (Box 236)
        - Appointments (Box 236)
        - Articles for Publication (Box 236)
        - Atomic Energy Study Commission (Box 236)
        - Automation (Box 236)
        - Bar (State) (Box 236)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 236)
        - Brussel's World's Fair Commission (Box 236)
        - Build Soon Committee (Box 236)
        - Cancer Fund Drive (Box 236)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 236)
        - Celebrations
          - General (Box 236)
          - Civil War Centennial (Box 236)
        - Certificate - Outgoing (Box 236)
        - Charter Amendments [A-C] (Box 236)
        - Charter Amendments [D-R] (Box 237)
        - Charter Amendments [S-W] (Box 238)
        - Civil Rights (Box 238)
        - Communism (Box 238)
        - Community Chest (Box 238)
        - Complaints [A-Z] (Box 238)
        - Conferences
          - General (Box 238)
          - National Rivers and Harbors Congress (Box 238)
          - National Tax Association (Box 238)
        - Constitution (Box 238)
        - Consulates (Box 238)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 238)
        - Counties [arranged alphabetically] (Box 238)
        - Countries [arranged alphabetically] (Box 238)
        - Detroit, City of (Box 238)
        - Detroit Metropolitan Area Regional Planning Commission (Box 238)
        - [Box number eliminated during the 1983-84 reprocessing of the Williams collection] (Box 239)
        - Disaster Relief (Box 240)
        - Divorce (Box 240)
        - Drains (Box 240)
        - Economic Advisory Group (Box 240)
        - Economic Future Commission (Box 240)
        - Elections, 2 folders (Box 240)
        - Employment [A-Z] (Box 240)
        - Executive Office (Box 240)
        - Executive Order (Box 240)
        - Flags (Box 240)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 240)
        - Fulbright Scholarship (Box 240)
        - Full Employment Committee (Box 240)
        - Gambling (Box 240)
        - Girl Scouts (Box 240)
        - Governor's Conference, 2 folders (Box 240)
        - Governor's Conference, 3 folders (Box 241)
        - Governor's Conference (Great Lakes States) (Box 241)
        - Grand Jury (Box 241)
        - Hawaii (Box 241)
        - Hi-Y (Box 241)
        - Honorary Membership (Box 241)
        - Housing (Box 241)
        - Housing Code Study Committee (Box 241)
        - Immigration (Box 241)
        - Income Tax (Box 241)
        - Industrial Production Committee
          - General (Box 241)
          - Missiles and Rockets (Box 241)
        - Infantile Paralysis (Box 241)
        - Interagency Council for Recreation (Box 241)
        - International Students Day, 1957-1958; 3 folders (Box 241)
        - International Students Day, 1957-1958; 11 folders (Box 242)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 242)
        - Invitations - Outgoing
          - General (Box 242)
          - Anti-Defamation League (Box 242)
        - Judgeship (Box 243)
        - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 243)
        - Labor (Box 243)
        - Legal Holidays (Box 243)
        - Legal Problems [A-Z] (Box 243)
        - Legislative Reapportionment (Box 243)
        - Legislature, Members of (Box 243)
        - Lobbyists (Box 243)
        - Maps (Box 243)
        - Message of Governor (Box 243)
        - Messages of Greeting (Box 243)
        - Metropolitan Problems (Box 243)
        - Migrant Labor (Box 244)
        - Music (Box 244)
        - Narcotics (Box 244)
        - Nationality Groups (Box 244)
        - Newspapers (Box 244)
        - Notary Public (Box 244)
        - Ordinances (Box 244)
        - Organizations (Box 244)
        - Personnel, Council, State (Box 244)
        - Philippine Islands (Box 244)
        - Physically Handicapped (Box 244)
        - Poet Laureate (Box 244)
        - Political [A-Z] (Box 244)
        - Political Job (Box 244)
        - Postmaster (Box 244)
        - Price Control (Box 244)
        - Program Information Council (Box 244)
        - Public Utilities (Box 244)
        - Public Works (Box 244)
        - Puerto Rico (Box 244)
        - Racial (Box 244)
        - Radio; TV, 2 folders (Box 244)
        - Recommendation (Box 244)
        - Red Cross (Box 244)
        - Red Stocking Club (Box 244)
        - Removal
          - General (Box 245)
          - Thomas S. Welsh (St. Clair Shores mayor) (Box 245)
        - Rent Control (Box 246)
        - Research Bulletins (Box 246)
        - Resolutions (Box 246)
        - Roads (Box 246)
        - Safety
          - General [A-Z] (Box 246)
          - Governor's Highway Safety Conference (Box 246)
        - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 246)
        - Savings Bonds (Box 246)
        - Science Advisory Board (Box 246)
        - Sex Deviates (Box 246)
        - Small Business Committee (Box 246)
        - Sponsor (Box 246)
        - Sputnik (Box 246)
        - State Ferries Employment Advisory Committee (Box 246)
        - Statements for Publication (Box 246)
        - States (Box 247)
        - Taxation
          - General [A-Z] (Box 247)
          - Re: Income Tax (Box 247)
          - Re: Industries (Box 247)
          - Intangible Tax [A-Z] (Box 247)
        - Taxation Study Commission (Box 247)
        - Transportation (Box 247)
        - Unemployment [A-Z] (Box 247)
        - Unemployment Compensation (Box 247)
        - Unions (Box 248)
        - United Nations (Box 248)
        - Vacancy (Box 248)
        - Water (Box 248)
        - Wolverine Boys State (Box 248)
        - Wolverine Girls State (Box 248)
        - Young American Medals (Box 248)
        - Youth Commission
          - General (Box 248)
          - White House Conference (Box 248)
        - Miscellaneous [A-H] (Box 248)
        - Miscellaneous [I-Z] (Box 249)
        - [Box number eliminated during the 1983-84 reprocessing of the Williams Collection] (Box 250)
      - Boards and Commissions
        - Accident Fund (Box 251)
        - Accountancy, State Board of (Box 251)
        - Administrative Board
          - General (Box 251)
          - Meeting Files, Jan.-Dec. (Box 251)
        - Administration, Department of
          - James Miller, Controller, Jan.-June (Box 251)
          - James Miller, Controller, July-Dec. (Box 252)
          - General (Box 252)
          - Audit and other reports (Box 252)
          - Memoranda with governor (Box 252)
          - General Departmental Communication No. 12 (Box 252)
          - Accounting Division (Box 252)
          - Building and Construction Division (Box 252)
          - Motor Transport Division (Box 252)
          - Property Manager Division (Box 252)
          - Purchasing Division (Box 252)
        - Aeronautics, Department of
          - General (Box 252)
          - Re: Federal Legislation (Box 252)
        - Agriculture, Department of
          - George McIntyre, Director (Box 252)
          - General (Box 252)
          - Re: Milk (Box 252)
          - Reports (Box 252)
          - Background material (Box 253)
        - Agriculture, State Board of (Box 253)
        - Alcoholism Board (Box 253)
        - Apple Commission (Box 253)
        - Architects, Board of Registration (Box 253)
        - Athletic, Board of Control (Box 253)
        - Attorney General
          - Paul Adams File (Box 253)
          - General (Box 253)
          - Opinions (Box 253)
        - Auditor General
          - Frank Szymanski File (Box 253)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 253)
        - Banking Commission
          - Alonzo Wilson, Commissioner (Box 253)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 253)
          - General (Box 253)
          - Re: Development Finance Corporation (Box 253)
        - Barbers, Board of Examiners
          - General (Box 253)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 253)
        - Basic Science, Board of Examiners (Box 253)
        - Bridge Commission (Box 253)
        - Building Commission (Box 253)
        - Chiropody, Board of Registration (Box 253)
        - Civil Service Commission
          - A. Rasch File (Box 253)
          - Minutes and background material (Box 253)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 253)
        - Colleges, State
          - General (Box 253)
          - Junior and Community College Study Commission (Box 253)
          - Central Michigan (Box 253)
          - Eastern Michigan (Box 253)
          - Ferris State (Box 253)
          - Michigan College of Mining and Technology (Box 253)
          - Michigan State University (Box 254)
          - Northern Michigan (Box 254)
          - University of Michigan (Box 254)
          - Wayne State (Box 254)
          - Western Michigan College (Box 254)
        - Conservation Department
          - Gerald Eddy, Director (Box 254)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 254)
          - Reports; Background Material (Box 254)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 254)
          - Interstate Oil Compact Commission (Box 254)
          - Lands Division (Box 254)
          - Meeting re state parks, March 18 (Box 254)
          - Parks and Recreation (Box 254)
          - Porcupine Mountain, 3 folders (Box 254)
        - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 254)
        - Corrections Department (Box 255)
          - Gus Harrison, Director (Box 255)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 255)
          - General (Box 255)
          - Audit Reports (Box 255)
          - Prisons (Box 255)
          - Inmates [A-R] (Box 255)
          - Inmates [S-Z] (Box 256)
          - Pardons and commutation Files [A-Z] (Box 256)
        - Cosmetology Board (Box 256)
        - Court of Claims Commission (Box 256)
        - Crippled Children Commission
          - General (Box 256)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 256)
        - Dentistry, Board of (Box 256)
        - Economic Development Department
          - Don Weeks, Director (Box 256)
          - Auto Sales Campaign (Box 256)
          - Re: Centennial Awards (Box 256)
          - Re: Industrial Ambassadors (Box 257)
          - Michigan Week (Box 257)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 257)
        - Education, State Board of
          - General (Box 257)
          - School for the Blind (Box 257)
          - School for the Deaf (Box 257)
        - Electrical Administrative Board (Box 257)
        - Employees Retirement Board, State
          - Frank Blackford, Executive Secretary (Box 257)
          - Social Security Referendum (Box 257)
        - Michigan Employment Security Commission
          - Max Horton, Director (Box 257)
          - Reports; Background Material (Box 257)
          - General (Box 257)
          - Legislative Investigation (Box 257)
          - Legislation (Box 257)
          - Citizen Mail [A-F] (Box 257)
          - Citizen Mail [G-Z] (Box 258)
          - Appeal Board (Box 258)
        - Equalization Board (Box 258)
        - Escheats, State Board of (Box 258)
        - Fairs, Board of Managers of State (Box 258)
        - Fair, Upper Peninsula Board of Managers (Box 258)
        - Fair Employment Practices Commission (Box 258)
        - Foresters Board of Registration (Box 258)
        - Great Lakes Commission (Box 258)
        - Great Lakes Tidewater Commission (Box 258)
        - Health Commission
          - Albert Heustis, Commissioner (Box 258)
          - Administrative Board Reports (Box 258)
          - Reports; Background Material (Box 258)
          - Interdepartmental Communications (Box 258)
          - Public Health Study Commission (Box 258)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 258)
        - Highway, Department of
          - John Mackie, Commissioner (Box 258)
          - Reports; Background Material (Box 258)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 258)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 259)
          - Re: Asphalt-Cement debate [A-Z] (Box 259)
        - Historical Commission (Box 259)
        - Hospital Survey and Construction
          - General (Box 259)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 259)
        - Insurance Commission
          - Joseph A. Navarre, Commissioner (Box 259)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 259)
          - Blue Cross Study Commission (Box 259)
          - General (Box 259)
        - Interstate Cooperation Commission (Box 260)
        - Judges Retirement Board (Box 260)
        - Labor Department
          - General (Box 260)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 260)
          - Industrial Safety Advisory Council (Box 260)
          - Re: Industrial Safety (Box 260)
        - Labor Mediation Board
          - General (Box 260)
          - Administration Reports (Box 260)
          - Re: Mercy Hospital (Box 260)
        - Law Examiners, Board of (Box 260)
        - Library, State (Box 260)
        - Lieutenant Governor (Box 260)
        - Liquor Control Commission
          - Joseph Wisniewski, Chairman (Box 260)
          - Re: Bowlerama Lanes (Box 260)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 260)
          - George Burke, Jr., Commissioner (Box 260)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 260)
        - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 260)
        - Mackinac Straits Bridge Authority
          - General (Box 260)
          - Reports; Miscellanea (Box 260)
          - Bridge Dedication, June (Box 261)
          - Re: Interlochen Controversy (Box 261)
          - Coins and First Day Covers (Box 261)
          - Invitations To Governors (Box 261)
        - Medicine, Board of Registration (Box 261)
        - Mental Health Department
          - Charles F. Wagg, Director (Box 261)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 261)
          - Audit Reports; Background Material (Box 261)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 261)
          - Re: DeNike Sanitarium (Box 261)
          - Hospitals
            - Caro (Box 261)
            - Coldwater (Box 261)
            - Ionia (Box 261)
            - Kalamazoo (Box 261)
            - Lapeer (Box 261)
            - Newberry (Box 261)
            - Northville (Box 261)
            - Pontiac (Box 261)
            - Traverse City (Box 261)
        - Mortuary Science Board (Box 261)
        - Municipal Employees Retirement Board (Box 261)
        - Municipal Finance Commission (Box 261)
        - Nurses and Trained Attendants, Board of Registration (Box 261)
        - Optometry, Board of Examiners (Box 261)
        - Osteopathic Registration and Examination, Board of (Box 262)
        - Pharmacy, Board of (Box 262)
        - Plumbing Board (Box 262)
        - Police, State
          - Joseph Childs, Commissioner (Box 262)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 262)
          - Reports (Box 262)
          - Accident Reports (Box 262)
          - Re: Justice of the Peace (Box 262)
          - Re: State Property Fire Safety Seminar (Box 262)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 262)
        - Port of Detroit (Box 262)
        - Port of Monroe (Box 262)
        - Private Employment Bureaus (Box 262)
        - Public Instruction
          - Lynn Bartlett, Superintendent (Box 262)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 262)
          - Educational Finance Study Commission (Box 262)
          - Higher Education (Box 262)
          - School Bonds
            - General (Box 262)
            - Meeting, January 6 (Box 262)
            - Meeting, March 24 (Box 262)
        - Public School Employee Retirement Board (Box 262)
        - Public Service Commission
          - Otis Smith, Chairman (Box 263)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 263)
        - Racing Commission
          - James H. Inglis, Commissioner (Box 263)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 263)
          - General (Box 263)
          - Re: Pari-Mutuel Betting (Box 263)
        - Revenue Department
          - General (Box 263)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 263)
          - Reports; Background Material (Box 263)
        - Safety Commission
          - Gerald Shipman, Executive Secretary (Box 263)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 263)
          - Reports; Background Material (Box 263)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 263)
          - Governor's Regional Highway Safety Conferences (Box 263)
          - President's Committee for Traffic Safety (Box 263)
          - Governors' Conference Committee on Highway Safety (Box 264)
          - Meeting Files, Jan.-Dec. (Box 264)
        - Secretary of State
          - James Hare (Box 264)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 264)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 264)
          - Re: Uninsured Motorists (Box 264)
        - Social Welfare Commission
          - W. J. Maxey, Director (Box 264)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 264)
          - Minutes (Box 264)
          - General (Box 264)
          - Boys Vocational School (Box 264)
          - Children's Institute (Box 264)
          - Girls Training School (Box 264)
          - Old Age Assistance: Claim on Property (Box 264)
          - Services for the Blind (Box 264)
          - Social Welfare letters [A-B] (Box 264)
          - Social Welfare letters [C-Z] (Box 265)
        - Soil Conservation Commission (Box 265)
        - Supreme Court (Box 265)
        - Tax Appeals, Board of (Box 265)
        - Tax Commission (Box 266)
        - Tenure Commission (Box 266)
        - Tourist Council
          - General (Box 266)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 266)
        - Treasurer, State (Box 266)
        - Tuberculosis Sanitorium Commission
          - General (Box 266)
          - Audit Reports (Box 266)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 266)
        - Turnpike Authority (Box 266)
        - Uniformity of Legislation In United States (Box 266)
        - Veterans Facility (Grand Rapids)
          - General (Box 266)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 266)
        - Veterinary Board (Box 266)
        - Vocational Rehabilitation, State Office of (Box 266)
        - Water Resources Commission
          - Milton Adams, Commissioner (Box 266)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 266)
          - General (Box 266)
          - Audit Report; Background Material (Box 266)
        - Waterways Commission
          - Keith Wilson, Director (Box 266)
          - General (Box 266)
          - Harbors of Refuge (Box 266)
          - Water Safety Study Committee (Box 267)
        - Workmen's Compensation Commission
          - Thomas Quimby, Director (Box 267)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 267)
          - General (Box 267)
          - Appeal Board (Box 267)
      - Legislative Files
        - Regular Session
          - Governor's Messages (and related), 2 folders (Box 348)
          - Bills Signed (Box 348)
          - Bills Vetoed (Box 348)
          - Legislative Summary, 2 folders (Box 348)
          - Memoranda re Bills (Box 348)
          - Memoranda re House Bills (Box 348)
          - Memoranda re Senate Bills (Box 348)
          - Constituent Mail (Box 349)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 349)
            - Liquor: 90 day credit (Box 349)
            - State Troops (Box 349)
            - Sunday Closing (Box 349)
            - Unemployment (Box 349)
          - Bill Files: House
            - Resolutions (joint) (Box 349)
            - Numbered Files
              - 1-202 (Box 349)
              - 203-563 (Box 350)
              - 564-589 (Box 351)
          - Bill Files: Senate
            - Resolution (concurrent) No. 20 (Box 351)
            - Resolutions (joint) (Box 351)
            - Numbered Files
              - 1001-1260 (Box 351)
              - 1261-1341 (Box 352)
        - Special Session, June 19, 1958
          - June 19, 1958 (Box 352)
      - Military
        - Adjutant General
          - General (Box 386)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 386)
        - Quartermaster General (Box 386)
        - Military Board (Box 386)
        - Civil Defense
          - Ralph Sheehan, Director (Box 386)
          - Administrative Reports (Box 386)
          - General (Box 386)
          - Applications (Box 386)
          - Continuity of Government (Box 386)
          - Meeting, Advisory Council (Box 386)
          - Printed Material (Box 386)
        - National Guard
          - General (Box 386)
          - Air Unit (Box 386)
          - Armories (Box 386)
        - State Troops (Box 386)
        - Veterans
          - General (Box 386)
          - Apprentice Training (Box 386)
          - Bonus (Box 386)
          - Hospitalization (Box 386)
          - Organizations (Box 386)
          - Veterans Trust Fund
            - Lawrence Lalone, Executive Secretary (Box 386)
            - General [A-R] (Box 386)
            - General [S-Z] (Box 387)
          - Veterans Vocational School (Box 387)
        - Selective Service (Box 387)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous
          - General [A-L] (Box 387)
          - General [M-Z] (Box 402)
        - Federal-State Intergovernmental Relations (Box 402)
        - U.S. Senate
          - General [A-Z] (Box 402)
          - McNamara, Patrick (Box 402)
        - U.S. Congress (Box 402)
        - Agriculture, Department of (Box 402)
        - Air Force (Box 402)
        - Army (Box 402)
        - Commerce, Department of (Box 402)
        - Defense, Department of (Box 402)
        - Federal Communications Commission (Box 402)
        - Federal Power Commission
          - General (Box 402)